

#### **PROFILE**

Junior software developer with work experience in my home country. Currently enrolled to university for Master's degree. As an employee, I am fast trainable, attentive to details and interested in new technologies, paradigms and programming languages. As a colleague, I am open-minded, collaborative. As a young specialist, I have advanced communication skills and entrepreneurial thinking.

#### CONTACT

PHONE: (+49) 17635706859

LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/nadezhda-sitdikova

EMAIL nadezhda.sitdikova@tu-ilmenau.de

## **ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS**

Swimming Travel Great food Cooking Literature Art

# Nadezhda Sitdikova

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Junior developer Craft Tables, Moscow

January 2021 - Present

Analyze and optimize the current business processes (BP) by automating them and determining bottlenecks. Develop bots for Telegram messenger in Python and JavaScript, that provide BP's automatization. Use RestAPI of different applications to get or post data through bots. Manage projects remotely with interdisciplinary software teams and stakeholders.

#### Development engineer Lexema. Ufa

September 2018 – February 2020

Modeled business processes using IDEFx, BPM, UML notations. Designed software architectures and algorithms for end-user's interaction depending on their roles and permissions. Tested the system according to the designed algorithms. Supported end-users and customers through training. Defined and tracked tasks for software developers in crossfunctional teams. Used languages and tools: SQL, JavaScript, VBA, React.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### TU Ilmenau

October 2021 – Present M.Sc. in Research in Computer and System Engineering

#### **Ufa State Aviation Technical University**

September 2013 – July 2018 B.Sc. in Applied Computer Science

#### **KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS**

- Advanced English
- Basic German
- JavaScript
- SQL, MySQL
- JSON
- Python
- UML
- BPMN
- Agile